# **Dmitry Kurmanov**

## **Senior Frontend Developer**

Armenia · +374 91 613143 · kurmanov.work@gmail.com · LinkedIn: dmitry-kurmanov · GitHub: dmitry-kurmanov

Making software for **10+ years** in small and medium companies: startups, product development, and outsourcing. Developed **6 successful web projects:** b2b JS SDK with **200.000 downloads per week**, medical technology, advertising, education tech, and mobile apps. Attracted **1000+ new clients** and **15+ large corporate clients** by solving business problems most efficiently. Being up to date with the best frontend instruments **saved 7000+ developer hours**. Passionating about sharing knowledge and ideas, wrote 7 tutorials, and delivered one public speech.

#### **SKILLS**

- **Frontend:** JavaScript / TypeScript, HTML (semantic), accessibility (WCAG), CSS (Flexbox, Grid), SASS, BEM, CSS animations, JS animations, responsive layout, mobile-first layout, Webpack, Rollup
- Frameworks: React, Redux, RTK, React-Router, Vue, Angular, Svelte, Knockout, Jquery, Material UI
- Software Development: Data structures and algorithms, design patterns, agile, TDD, system design
- Environment: Azure Dev, NPM, GitHub, Jest, Cypress, Playwright, QUnit, TestCafe, Figma, Zeplin
- Knowledge sharing: Tutorials writing, public speaking, onboarding process, review

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Senior Frontend Developer**

Jun 2020 - Now

SurveyJS - Open-Source JS SDK, B2B, Form Management System

- Developed NPM packages with **60.000+ downloads per week** by creating SurveyJS implementations for React, Vue, and Knockout frameworks
- **Brought 15+ large clients** in government and healthcare with accessibility requirements by heading the project's accessibility direction and compliance with WCAG A, AA, and AAA standards
- Reduced client issues with new releases up to 0 and saved up to 8 developer hours weekly by implementing a one-click automated release architecture using Azure DevOps, ensuring integrity with a single button click
- Gave a public speech about Azure Devops CI/CD processes in SurveyJS (Auto subtitles, Russian Lang)

## **Middle+ Frontend Developer**

Sep 2016 - Jun 2020

SurveyJS - Open-Source JS SDK, B2B, Form Management System

- Attracted 300+ new clients by developing complex drag-and-drop functionality, a key UX feature
- Saved 200+ developer hours and enhanced team atmosphere by creating a CMS and "How to Use" tutorial, enabling non-technical team members to independently create content for surveyis.io
- Saved 4.000+ developer hours by implementing the BEM methodology, reducing visual regression bug fixes

#### **Frontend Course Co-Author**

**Aug 2022 – Oct 2022 (Contract)** 

SkillFactory.ru - Education Technology, Frontend-Dev-Pro Course

• Taught 30+ people by creating the TS Advanced and E2E Testing course's module (theory, practice, test)

## **Middle Frontend Developer**

May 2015 - Sep 2016

**CoMagic.ru** - Product Development, Advertising Analysis Single-Page-Application

- Attracted 10+ new clients through the development new pages in the SPA advertising analytics application
- Reduced bug-fixing workload by 20% by refactoring one .css file (2.000+ rows) into feature-specific .scss files
- Promoted ReactJS to the team to improve product growth, leading to a transition to ReactJS after my leaving

### Middle Frontend Developer (Mobile)

Feb 2014 - May 2015

Smartech LLC - Outsource, Web-View-based Mobile Applications

- Attracted 2 new orders for mobile applications by developing two cross-platform mobile apps
- Developed the HomsBox, the discount application, has 50.000+ downloads in Google Play now

#### **EDUCATION**

 Tula State University, Tula, Russia Master's Degree, Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation Engineering, 2012

#### **CERTIFICATES**

• JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Freecodecamp, 2023

#### **PROJECTS**

• Auth Form - Beautiful login form with full accessibility support and great UX.